The most astonishing, innovative, backyard adventure of all time!
Honey, I Shrunk the Kids is a adventure, comedy,
family film directed by Joe Johnston.
The scientist father of a teenage girl and boy accidentally shrinks his
and two other neighborhood teens to the size of insects.
Now the teens must fight diminutive dangers as the father searches for them.
Wayne Szalinski, played by Rick Moranis.
Big Russ Thompson, played by Matt Frewer.
Diane Szalinski, played by Marcia Strassman.
Mae Thompson, played by Kristine Sutherland.
Little Russ Thompson, played by Thomas Wilson Brown.
Ronald Thompson, played by Jared Rushton.
Honey, I Shrunk the Kids is an American science fiction comedy media franchise, based on a concept created by
Stuart Gordon and Brian Yuzna, and an original story co-written by Gordon, Yuzna, and Ed Naha.
The franchise focuses around the Szalinski family, particularly the father, Wayne Szalinski, who is
a struggling inventor whose inventions unintentionally cause trouble and mishaps.
The first installment, Honey, I Shrunk the Kids (1989), and its subsequent financial and critical success, led to two sequels and a television series;
Honey, I Blew Up the Kid (1992), Honey, We Shrunk Ourselves (1997), and Honey, I Shrunk the Kids: The TV Show (1997–2000), respectively.
A fourth film titled Shrunk entered production in
2019 and is in development limbo.
This continued in 1999 when the Honey, I Shrunk the Kids films, along with a number of other Disney film series, were
combined into a franchise as a part of Disney Parks' attractions where elements from each movie were included.
The film explores themes of inventor, parent child
relationship, ant, shrinking, giant insect.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.